Register of the Ardashīr Zāhidī papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Ambassador to the United States File, 1970-1979
  - Embassy files, 1970-1978
    - Iranian correspondence, 1973-1978
      - Yigānah, Muḥammad, 1971-1977 (Box 135, Folder 4-5)
      - Yār Afshār, Parvīz, 1973-1978 (Box 135, Folder 6-12)
      - Unfiled letters, 1975, 1978 (Box 135, Folder 13)
    - Telegraphs, 1973-1978
      Includes incoming telegraphs and responses.
      - Nowruz, 1973-1978
        Includes inventory of senders, letters and cards.
        - 1973 March-April (Box 136)
        - 1974 March-April (Box 138, Folder 1-2, Box 137)
        - 1975 March-April (Box 139, Folder 1-6, Box 138, Folder 3-14)
        - 1976 March-May (Box 139, Folder 7-15, Box 141, Folder 1, Box 140)
        - 1977 March (Box 141, Folder 2-7)
        - 1978 March-April (Box 143, Folder 1-6, Box 141, Folder 8-15, Box 142)
      - 28 Mordad and anniversary of father's death, 1973-1975
        - 1973 August-September (Box 143, Folder 7-15, Box 144, Folder 1-4)
        - 1974 August-September (Box 144, Folder 5-7)
        - 1975 August-September (Boxes 238, Box 144, Folder 8-14)
      - 28 Mordad, anniversary of father's death, and birthday, 1976-1978
        - 1976 August-October (Box 145, Folder 1-4, Box 144, Folder 15-16)
        - 1977 August-October (Boxes 145, Folder 5-12)
        - 1978 August-October (Box 145, Folder 13-16, Box 146, Folder 1-5, Boxes 239, 245)
          Includes Persian language clippings about Zahedi and the anniversary of the 28 Mordad coup, and posters of the Shah.
      - Manṣūr Rafīʻzādah, 1976 October 19 (Box 146, Folder 6)
        Also spelled Mansur Rafizadeh.
    - Crown Prince files, 1978-1979
      - Letters from the Shah to the Crown Prince, 1978 October 17 (Box 147, Folder 1)
        Photocopy of one letter and a note from the Pahlavi family to Reza.
      - Reports about the Crown Prince, 1978 August (Box 147, Folder 2)
        Includes copies of letters from Zahedi to the Shah and Farah and government officials, a declassified document about Reza's flight training, and copies of photographs.
      - Letter from Zahedi to the Crown Prince, 1978 February 14 (Box 147, Folder 3)
      - Ministry of the Royal Court correspondence, 1978 (Box 147, Folder 4-5)
        Correspondence is largely with Amir Aslan Afshar and Fazlollah Nabil. Includes receipts and guest list for dinner.
      - Incoming letters to the Crown Prince, 1978 September-October (Box 147, Folder 6)
      - Clippings, 1978 June-July (Box 147, Folder 7-8)
      - Telegraphs, 1978 (Box 147, Folder 9-14)
        Largely between Zahedi and Moeinian, as well as a letter from Ernest Graves.
      - American correspondence, 1978 (Box 147, Folder 15)
        Includes correspondence with members of the United States Air Force.
      - Training progress reports, 1978 (Box 147, Folder 16-17)
        Includes memoranda, schedules, photographic prints, and slide related to Reza Pahlavi's Air Force training.
      - Financial records, 1978-1979
        - Security, 1978-1979 (Box 147, Folder 18)
        - Trips, 1978 (Box 147, Folder 19-20)
        - Staff salaries, 1978-1979 (Box 148, Folder 1)
        - Court correspondence, 1978 (Box 148, Folder 2)
      - General file, 1978 (Box 148, Folder 3-6)
        Includes correspondence (with members of the United States Air Force and the United States Air Force Academy), schedules, and other logistical documents, as well as printed material from the United States Air Force Academy.
      - Crown Prince visit letters, 1978 (Box 149, Folder 1-12, Box 148, Folder 7-14)
        Consists of incoming letters to Reza Pahlavi and Zahedi with Zahedi's responses. Includes photographs of Reza Pahlavi. Correspondents include Air Force officials, touristic staff, and the public.
      - Military personnel letters, 1978 (Box 150, Folder 1, Box 149, Folder 13-15)
    - Personal file, 1975-1977 (Box 150, Folder 2-4)
      Includes correspondence (some with family members), notes, and texts from speeches.
    - Ambassador schedules, circa 1977-1978 (Box 150, Folder 5-7)
    - Embassy telephone directory, 1976 (Box 150, Folder 8)
      - Other collected materials, circa 1973-1978
        - Guest lists, 1977 June 22 and undated (Box 154, Folder 4)
        - Jokes, circa 1973-1978 (Box 154, Folder 5)
        - Letter and report, 1978 September 7 (Box 154, Folder 6)
          From Yusuf Akbar and Assad Homayoun.
        - Licenses, tags, and pins, circa 1973-1978 (Box 154, Folder 7)
        - News programs, 1977 April (Box 154, Folder 8)
          Consists of news summary and news schedule.
        - Religious handbills, circa 1973-1978 (Box 154, Folder 9)
        - Stenographic Transcript of Hearings before the Committee on Foreign Relations, United States Senate: Business Meeting, 1977 October 11 (Box 154, Folder 10)
    - Ambassador business cards, circa 1973-1978 (Box 150, Folder 9)
    - Embassy stationary, circa 1973-1978 (Box 150, Folder 10)
    - Speeches and interviews, 1967-1978 (Box 150, Folder 11-14, Box 151, Folder 1-2)
      Includes clipping booklets about Zahedi's public appearances and interviews, printed compilations of his interviews and speeches, and transcripts or printouts of individual speeches.
    - Writings, 1977, undated
      - "Five Decisive Days: August 14-18, 1953", typescripts, undated (Box 151, Folder 3-5)
      - Five Decisive Days: Iran, August 14-18, 1953, Washington D.C., 1977 (Box 151, Folder 6)
        Photocopy.
    - Embassy publications, 1961-1977
      - Akhbār-i Īrān, 1975 June-July (Box 152, Folder 1)
      - Iran Review, 1960-1961 (Box 152, Folder 2)
      - Persian Panorama, 1965, 1974 (Box 152, Folder 3)
        1965 issue is from the Embassy of Iran, London.
      - Profile on Iran, 1975 July (Box 152, Folder 4)
      - State visits, 1973-1975 (Box 152, Folder 5)
        Embassy publications about state visits.
      - Farah Pahlavi interviews and speech, 1975-1977 (Box 152, Folder 6)
    - Financial records, 1973-1978
      Includes the embassy's commercial correspondence, communications with the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, and receipts.
      - Niyāzmand, Riz̤ā, 1973-1978 (Box 152, Folder 7-11)
        Also spelled Reza Niyazmand. Includes correspondence between Zahedi and Niyazmand and government and company reports about Securitas.
      - Dawlatshāhī, Shāpūr, 1973-1978 (Box 153, Folder 1-2, Box 152, Folder 12-16)
        Includes correspondence, documents related to social events, and receipts.
      - Bānk-i Īrān va Ingilīs, 1973 (Box 153, Folder 3)
        Consists of bank reports.
      - Consulate General in New York, 1973-1976 (Box 153, Folder 4)
      - Lion and sun gifts, 1973-1978 (Box 153, Folder 5-8)
        "Sweden account."
      - Gifts and gold coins, 1973 (Box 153, Folder 9)
      - Gifts and watches, 1973-1978 (Box 153, Folder 10-11)
      - Omar Khayyam book, 1973-1978 (Box 153, Folder 12)
      - Henry Poole account, 1973-1974 (Box 153, Folder 13)
      - Nicaragua earthquake relief, 1973-1974 (Box 153, Folder 14)
      - Vittorio Candusso, 1973-1974 (Box 153, Folder 15)
      - Rosenthal account, 1973-1978 (Box 153, Folder 16-17)
      - Hesarak, 1973-1978 (Box 153, Folder 18-19)
        Includes correspondence, property plan, and financial documents.
      - Embassy finances, 1973-1978 (Box 154, Folder 1-3)
    - Printed materials, 1973-1978
      Includes clippings, magazines and newspapers.
      - By subject, 1975-1977
        - Kissinger, Henry, circa 1976 (Box 154, Folder 11)
        - Reagan, Ronald, 1975 December 30 (Box 154, Folder 12)
        - Taylor, Elizabeth, 1976 (Box 154, Folder 13)
          Includes photograph of Taylor.
        - Zāhidī, Ardashīr, 1975-1977 (Box 154, Folder 14-16)
      - By title, circa 1973-1977
        - Marzʹhā-yi Naw, circa 1973 (Box 154, Folder 17)
        - Souvenir Book, 17th Annual United Nations Concert and Dinner, 1977 (Box 154, Folder 18)
      - Chronological, 1976-1978
        Includes clipping booklets and newspapers. Subjects include Iran and the Shah.
        - 1976 (Box 154, Folder 19-20)
        - 1977 (Box 154, Folder 21)
        - 1978 (Box 154, Folder 22)
- Career after Diplomacy File, 1979-2014
  Contains materials from Zahedi's time in Switzerland following his diplomatic career. Materials have been arranged by form and chronologically. The first correspondence and printed material subseries are focused on political developments related to revolutionary Iran, followed by the writings subseries and later correspondence and printed material.
  - Notes, circa 1980s (Box 155, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1982
    Includes clippings about Zahedi, the Pahlavi family, political developments in Iran and the Iranian hostage crisis. Arranged by sender.
    - Chronological, 1979-1980 (Box 155, Folder 2-3)
    - Atabai, K., 1979 (Box 155, Folder 4)
    - Cottrell, Alvin J., 1976-1980 (Box 155, Folder 5)
    - Franzheim, Susan Beth, 1979-1980 (Box 155, Folder 6-8)
    - Galindo, Gabriel Lewis, 1979 June 19 (Box 155, Folder 9)
    - Hishāmtī, Kāmrān, 1980 October-November (Box 155, Folder 10)
      Includes issue of Īrān-i Niyūz.
    - Iran Freedom Foundation, 1979-1980 (Box 155, Folder 11-12)
      Includes media reports from interviews with Ali A. Tabatabai, copies of statements from Tabatabai, and "Report of the Staff's Study of Alleged Misconduct by Members of the House of Representatives Involving the Former Government of Iran."
    - Larsen, Thelma, 1980-1981 (Box 155, Folder 13)
    - Marshall, Sylvan, 1979-1981 (Box 155, Folder 14)
    - Nashat, Mahyar, 1979 April (Box 155, Folder 15)
    - Powell, Diana Kearny, 1979-1981 (Box 156, Folder 1-6, Box 155, Folder 16-18)
    - Reed, Joseph Verner, 1979-1981 (Box 156, Folder 7-8)
    - Ribicoff, Casey, 1979 March-May (Box 156, Folder 9)
    - Rockefeller, David, 1979 (Box 156, Folder 10)
      Includes Rockefeller's statement about the Shah.
    - Sadat, Anwar, circa 1979-1980 (Box 238)
      Envelopes, no actual letters.
    - Sadjadi, 1973, 1979-1982 (Box 156, Folder 11)
    - Victor, Robert C., 1980 (Box 156, Folder 12-13)
  - Telegraphs, 1979-1980 (Box 156, Folder 14)
  - Interview transcripts, 1980-1981 (Box 156, Folder 15-16)
    Consists of Persian notes for Bertil Galland's interview with the Shah and typed transcripts of Barbara Walters's interview with Ashraf Pahlavi.
  - Printed material, 1979-1994
    - Clippings, 1979-1981
      - Booklet, 1979 January-February (Box 157, Folder 1)
        Photocopies of clippings, including interviews with Zahedi and a statement by Shapour Bakhtiar.
      - 1979 (Box 157, Folder 2-4)
      - 1980 (Box 157, Folder 5-12)
      - 1981 (Box 157, Folder 13)
    - Newspapers, chronological, 1979-1981
      - 1979 (Box 157, Folder 14)
      - 1980 (Box 157, Folder 15, Box 159, Folder 1-4, Box 158)
      - 1981 (Box 159, Folder 5-6)
    - Newspapers and magazines, 1979-1988
      - Ārā: Urgān-i Artish-i Rahāʼī Bakhsh-i Īrān, 1979 October-November (Box 160, Folder 1)
        Shumārah-i 2-3, sal-i yakum.
      - Iʻdām: Urgān-i āzādigān-i Īrān, 1988 March 21 (Box 160, Folder 2)
        Title also spelled Eadam. Sāl-i dahhum, shumārah-i 400. Shumārah-i makhsus-i nawruz.
      - Iṭṭilāʻāt-i Haftagī, 1982 August 25 (Box 238)
      - Jours de France, 1980 August 2-8 (Box 238)
      - Life, 1980 January (Box 238)
      - MEED. Middle East Economic Digest, 1979 July-August (Box 160, Folder 3)
      - Newsletter. Iran Center for Documentation, 1980 June, September (Box 160, Folder 4)
      - Newsweek, 1979-1981 (Box 160, Folder 5)
      - New York Times Magazine, 1981 (Box 238)
      - Now!, 1979-1981 (Box 160, Folder 6-7)
      - Qiyām-i Īrān, 1986 October 9 (Box 160, Folder 8)
        Also spelled Qyam Iran.
      - The Review of the News, 1979 February 21 (Box 160, Folder 9)
      - Stop: Settimanale di Attualita Politica e Cultura, 1980 August 8 (Box 160, Folder 10)
      - Strategy Week, 1980 August 4-10 (Box 160, Folder 11)
      - Time, 1981 January 29 (Box 160, Folder 12)
      - U.S. News & World Report, 1980-1981 (Box 160, Folder 13-14)
      - Washington Journalism Review, 1980 October (Box 160, Folder 15)
  - Writings, 1940s-2014
    - Edited works, 1981-2004
      - Shawcross, William. The Shah's Last Ride, draft, 1987-1988 (Box 161, Folder 1-11)
        Includes accompanying letters.
      - Ṣafāʼī, Ibrāhīm. Zindagīnāmah-ʼi Sipahbud Zāhidī, draft and review, circa 1994-1995 (Box 161, Folder 12-13)
        Includes accompanying printed material, including book review and carbon copy of letter to Zahedi.
      - Book contracts, 1994-1995 (Box 161, Folder 14)
      - Humāyūnfar, ʻIzzat Allāh. Az sipāhīgarī tā siyāsatmadārī: zindagī-i Sipahbud Faz̤l Allāh Zāhidī, drafts and background materials, 1981-1998 (Box 161, Folder 15, Boxes 162-164, Box 165, Folder 1-13)
        Includes accompanying correspondence; notes and notebooks; printed background materials; reprints, negatives, and printouts from various stages of Fazlollah's life with notes; and photographs of Ardeshir, Fazlollah, and Mahnaz Zahedi, Maḥmūd Āyram, and Luṭf Allāh Khān.
      - Unknown manuscript, 2004 (Box 166, Folder 1-2, Box 165, Folder 14-17)
        Text is about Iranian politics and Mohammad Mosaddegh.
    - Memoirs, 1940s-2014
      Includes drafts and assembled photographs and documents.
      - Draft, undated (Box 166, Folder 3)
        Handwritten, possibly in someone else's hand, chiefly about Fazlollah.
      - Volume I, English translation, cover and promotional material, 2012-2013 (Box 166, Folder 4)
      - Volume II, English translation, drafts, 2014 and undated (Box 166, Folder 5-7, Box 167, Folder 1)
      - Volume I, French translation, cover and introduction proofs, 2009 May 18 (Box 167, Folder 2)
      - Notes, undated (Box 167, Folder 3)
        Notes in Persian regarding Zahedi's memories about Mansour Ordoobadi and Mohammad Khan Akbar.
      - File 1, 1974-2001 (Box 167, Folder 4-6)
        Includes photographic prints, reprints, and negatives of Ardeshir from different stages of his life and career, as well as of Abu Al-Qasim, Fazlollah, and Mahnaz Zahedi; Shahnaz, Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, and other members of the Pahlavi family; İhsan Sabri Çağlayangil, Richard Nixon, Ronald Reagan, and Betty and Gerald Ford. Also includes copies of newspaper articles and inventory of photos to be used in first volume of his memoirs. Many of the pictures have notes attached or written on the back.
      - File 2, circa 2001 (Box 167, Folder 7)
        Includes duplicates of photographs related to his father and the 1953 Mordad coup, the Pahlavis, his first appointment in the United States, and his time as Minister of Foreign Affairs.
      - File 3, circa 1966-1977, 2003 (Box 167, Folder 8-10)
        Includes photographs and reprints from Zahedi's time as Minister of Foreign Affairs and his second appointment in the United States. Includes photographs of Ardeshir and Fawzia, the Shah and Farah Pahlavi, Gerald and Betty Ford, Ashraf Ghorbal, Anwar Sadat, and Jimmy and Rosalynn Carter. Also includes copies of decrees and orders related to his father (1925-1958), most of which are found in other research files.
      - Ambassador to the United Kingdom, circa 1953-2004 (Box 167, Folder 11-14, Box 243)
        Includes photographs and duplicates from his time as Ambassador to the United Kingdom, including images of Sir Edward Heath, Lord Mountbatten, Abdullah and Mrs. Malikyar, and Queen Elizabeth, as well as photographs and duplicates related to his father and the 1953 coup, and his youth.
      - Documents related to Volume II, circa 1940s-2004 (Box 168, Folder 1-5)
        Includes letters to Fazlollah from Daftar-i Makhsus and Shahnaz Pahlavi; one letter from Shams Pahlavi; Fazlollah's writings, message from Fazlollah Zahedi to General Riahi, General Razavi (?), and Colonel Ashrafi, on August 19th, 1953, informing them that Fazlollah has seized power and for them to follow General Batmanglitch; copy of letter written during internment in Palestine; copies of State Department documents and Shah's orders; clippings and newspaper articles; and notes related to material selection.
      - Photographs for Mansore and Daryoush Pirnia, 1958-2004 (Box 168, Folder 6-8)
        Includes photographic prints, duplicates, and negatives related to Ardeshir and Mahnaz Zahedi, Shahnaz, Farah, and Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, Queen Elizabeth, and Lord and Lady Hartley Shawcross, as well as a newspaper interview with Zahedi in the Washington Times from 1984.
      - Zahedi with politicians and heads of state, circa 1970s-2001 (Box 168, Folder 9-14)
        Includes reprints and photographs from Ardeshir's time as Foreign Minister and Ambassador, including RCD meetings and meetings in Cairo. Includes photograps of Ardeshir, Homa, and Mahnaz Zahedi, and Farah Pahlavi. Some of these images could have been compiled for or by Farīdūn Zandfard ("Az kitāb-i Zandfard.")
      - Assembled documents, circa 1970s (Box 168, Folder 15)
        Includes handbill from the hajj and copy of letter from Mohammed Reza Pahlavi to Amir-Abbas Hoveyda.
      - Mohammed Reza Pahlavi writing, undated (Box 168, Folder 16)
        Typewritten, signed with handwritten comments. About his father, Reza Shah, and the 1921 Persian coup d'état.
      - Letters, 1960, 2004 (Box 168, Folder 17)
        Includes photograph of Ardeshir with Shahnaz Pahlavi.
      - Notes, circa 2003-2004 (Box 168, Folder 18)
        Includes notes related to photographs.
      - Photographs, circa 1965-1985 (Box 243, Box 168, Folder 19)
        Includes photographs of Ardeshir, Shahnaz, Reza, and Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, Gholam H. Kazemian, and Nusrat and Benazir Bhutto.
      - Photograph reprints, circa 2000s (Box 243, Box 169, Folder 1-8)
      - Photocopies, circa 2000s (Box 169, Folder 9-17, Box 244)
        Photocopies of photographs and accompanying notes, as well as news articles relevant for his memoirs.
      - Printouts, 2004 (Box 170, Folder 1-2)
        Consists of printouts of Zahedi's photo collection with notes.
    - Letter to the New York Times, 2000 April-May (Box 170, Folder 3)
      Drafts of Zahedi's letter in response to article by James Risen on the 1953 coup. Includes additional newspaper articles written during this time.
    - Interviews, 2000-2009 (Box 170, Folder 4-10)
      Includes articles, interview texts, questions, answers, and notes from interviews. In English, Persian, and French.
    - Articles, 2004-2005 (Box 170, Folder 11)
  - Subject and research file, circa 1945-2008
    Mostly printed matter, arranged by archivist.
    - 28 Mordad coup, circa 1953-2000s (Box 170, Folder 12)
      Includes "Pictorial events of Iran" and Persian articles.
    - Ardashīr Zāhidī, 1959-2008 (Box 170, Folder 13, Box 245)
    - Bahrain, 1986 (Box 170, Folder 14)
    - British Embassy documents, 1955-1961 (Box 242)
      Photocopies.
    - Department of State documents, 1960-1973, 2001 (Box 170, Folder 15-16)
      Consists of photocopies of declassified telegraphs, memoranda, and letters about Ardeshir, Iran's foreign relations, Middle Eastern politics, the Pahlavi government and state visits.
    - Fawziya, 2004 and undated (Box 171, Folder 1)
    - Faz̤l Allāh Zāhidī, circa 1945-1993 (Box 171, Folder 2, Boxes 240-242)
      Includes printed material, photocopies of documents from his political career, reprints of photographs, and eight volumes of assembled clippings related to different stages of his career.
    - German articles, 1953-1993 (Box 171, Folder 3)
    - Iranian economy, circa 1980s (Box 171, Folder 4)
    - Iranian politics, 1953, 1980s-2005 (Box 171, Folder 5)
      Includes statement from the Iran Committee for the Defence of the Realm.
    - Iranian reports, 1978 and undated (Box 171, Folder 6-7)
      Consists of reports about economic conditions and infrastructure projects such as healthcare and construction.
    - Italian articles, 1958-1962 (Box 257)
    - Mahdī Vakīl correspondence, 1958-1971, 1992 (Box 171, Folder 8-11)
      Includes photocopies of Vekil's correspondence with the Minister of the Royal Court (Hossein Ala') and Ardeshir.
    - Mohammad Mosaddeq, 1978 and undated (Box 171, Folder 12)
    - Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, circa 1959-1999 (Box 171, Folder 13)
    - Peter Ramsbotham and Loy W. Henderson oral history transcripts, 1973, 1985 (Box 171, Folder 14)
    - Shahnāz Pahlavī, circa 1957-1964 (Box 171, Folder 15)
      Photocopies of articles.
    - Westminster College speech, 1977, 2000s (Box 171, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1984-2009
    - Chronological, 1993-2009 (Box 171, Folder 17-18)
    - Chase, Alice and Peter, 1984, 2002 (Box 171, Folder 19)
    - Cooley, John K. and Vania, 2007-2009 (Box 171, Folder 20)
    - Ghaffārī, ʻAbbās, 2004 (Box 172, Folder 1)
    - Raisian, John, 2006 (Box 172, Folder 2)
    - Tihrānī, Aḥmad, 1989, 1992-2003 (Box 172, Folder 3-4)
      Also spelled Tehrani. Includes sketch for bust of Fazlollah and accompanying printed material.
  - Miscellaneous, circa 2004 (Box 172, Folder 5)
    Includes hotel brochure and Iranian stamps.
  - Printed material, 1991-2006
    - Clippings, 2006 (Box 172, Folder 6)
    - Newspapers and magazines, 1991-1995
      - Asian Affairs: Journal of the Royal Central Asian Society, 1991 October (Box 172, Folder 7)
      - Iṭṭilāʻāt, 1995 August 16-19 (Box 172, Folder 8)
    - Books, 1994-2006
      - Khusravānī, Aṭā Allāh. Murūrī bar kitāb-i muʻammā-yi Huvaydā, 2003 (Box 172)
        براستی هویدا کی بود؟
      - Nahavandi, Houchang. Iran: The Clash of Ambitions, 2006 (Box 172)
      - Ṣafāʼī, Ibrāhīm. Zindagīnāmah-ʼi Sipahbud Zāhidī, 1994 (Box 172)
      - Warne, William E. Mission for Peace: Point 4 in Iran, 1999 (Box 172)
- Photographs, circa 1915-2000s
  Includes photographs and albums from Fazlollah's youth through Ardeshir's second appointment in the United States. Although different stages of Ardeshir's (and Fazlollah's) life and career are documented, including his wedding and his first appointment in the United States, his second appointment in the United States is the most documented aspect of his life. Other areas of interest include photographs from the 1953 coup and of the Pahlavis.
  - Labelled photographs, circa 1940s-2000s
    Arrangement Statement
    Original order has been maintained.
    - Ambassador's photographs, 1973-1978 (Box 173, Folder 1-16, Box 244)
      Consists mostly of portraits of Ardeshir, as well as portraits of Reza Pahlavi, and photographs of a tour group in Iran, Farah and Mohammad Reza Pahlavi, and Gerald Ford.
    - Pahlavi family, circa 1973-1975 (Box 173, Folder 17-20, Box 174, Folder 1-4, Box 236)
      Includes photographic prints and negatives of Ardeshir, Ali-Reza, Farah, Farahnaz, Laila, Reza, and Mohammed Reza Pahlavi.
    - State visit, 1973 (Box 174, Folder 5-7)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir, Mohammed Reza and Farah Pahlavi, Richard and Pat Nixon, J. William Fulbright, George D. Aiken, Edmund S. Muskie (members of the Senate Foreign Relation Committee), and Adele and William P. Rogers.
    - Farah Pahlavi in the United States, 1975 (Box 174, Folder 8-21)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir, Robert Orville Anderson, Mr. and Mrs. James E. "Ted" Bassett, Dan Chandler, Albery Clay, Mr. and Mrs. William S. Evans, J. B. Faulconer, Gerald and Betty Ford, Abbas Ghaffari, Edward Kennedy, Henry Kissinger, Wayne Murty, Rudolf Nureyev, Michael Phillips, Mr. and Mrs. Frederick Van Lennep, and Charles Woodruff Yost. Photographs were taken in Washington D.C., Colorado, and Chicago.
    - Reception for Farah Pahlavi in Mexico, 1975 (Box 174, Folder 22)
      Includes photographs of Ardeshir, as well as José and Carmen Romano López Portillo.